Register of the Russkoe sel'sko-khoziaistvennoe obshchestvo Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Russkoe sel'sko-khoziaistvennoe obshchestvo records,
1935-1948
2000C15
Russkoe sel'sko-khoziaistvennoe obshchestvo
4 microfilm reels (0.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, minutes, and reports, relating to Russian émigré participation in agriculture in the United States and Canada.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Administrative History
Association of émigré Russian agronomists in North America.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the correspondence and office file of the Russkoe sel'sko-khoziaistvennoe obshchestvo (Russian Agricultural Union of North America). Of particular interest are the issues of its bulletins, including the file of unpublished article drafts, which illustrate the breadth of its members' interests and activities. The correspondence is also a significant resource for the study of the contributions of Russian émigré agronomists and engineers to American and Canadian agricultural production and food processing (particularly grain, dairy products and spirits).
The correspondence is largely between the organization's founder, Petr Filaretovich Konstantinov, and its members, including V. M. Benzin, I. V. Emelianov, I. K. Okulich, M. T. Zarotschenzeff and others.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Agriculture--United States.; Agriculture--Canada.; Russians--United States.; Russians--Canada.; Russia.; United States.; Canada.
Series Description
- Correspondence, 1937-1948. (Box 1-2)
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence relating to the formation and activities of the association, arranged chronologically
- Office File, 1935-1947. (Box 3-4)
  Consists mainly of organizational materials, minutes of meetings, annual statements, lists of members and miscellaneous correspondence, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Also includes issues of the organization's bulletin and unpublished articles written for it
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1937-1948 (Box 1)
  - Incoming
    - 1937 December 8 - 1938 July (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1938 July - 1939 July 1 (Folder 1: 2)
    - 1939 July 1 - 1940 January 1 (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1940 January 1 - 1941 January 1 (Folder 1: 4)
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1944-1948 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Outgoing
    - 1937 December - 1939 June (Folder 2: 2)
    - 1939-1947 (Folder 2: 3)
- OFFICE FILE, 1935-1947 (Box 3)
  - Activity reports, 1938-1939 (Folder 3: 1)
  - Annual report, 1939 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Founding documents. (Folder 3: 3)
    Includes drafts of charter, appeals for support to Russian agronomists abroad, 1935-1938
  - Membership list, 1940 February 10 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1938-1945 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Publications
    - Izvestiia Russkogo sel'sko-khoziaistvennogo obshchestva
      - General. (Folder 3: 6)
        Drafts of articles submitted for publication and related materials
      - Issues #1-7, 1939-1941. (Folder 3: 7)
        Printed copies
      - Miscellany. (Folder 3: 8)
        Includes reviews
    - Katalog russkikh knig biblioteki Russkogo sel'sko-khoziaistvennogo obshchestva v Sev. Amerike, 1939. (Folder 3: 9)
      Printed copy
    - Obzor deiatel'nosti za 1938 g., 1939. (Folder 3: 10)
      Printed copy. Includes correspondence between V. A. fon Reimers and P. F. Konstantinov and I. K. Okulich, 1940, originally bound or placed into the volume
  - Scrapbooks
    - "O sel'skom khoz-ve Ameriki." (Folder 3: 11)
      Includes clippings, mainly from Russian émigré newspapers, regarding the state of farming and agricultural production in the United States. Also includes many articles by P. F. Konstantinov
    - "Russkoe sel'sko-khoziaistvennoe obshchestvo v Amerike." (Box-folder 4: 1)
      Includes clippings, photographs and the resumes or vitaes of members, as well as the charter, minutes of meetings, and annual reports of the organization
  - Subject file
    - Agriculture (Folder 4: 2)
    - Poultry. (Folder 4: 3)
      Includes notes and correspondence on poultry production
    - Russian Center (Russkii tsentr), San Francisco (Folder 4: 4)
    - Seeds--Soviet Union. (Folder 4: 5)
      Correspondence, notes and writings relating to transportation of seeds to the Soviet Union during the Second World War
  - Miscellany. (Folder 4: 6)
    Includes drafts of appeals, proposals, projects and speeches, memoranda, notes, and receipts